tonight on unplugged where we cut through the noise no scripts no filters just
the truth what an exciting episode of unplugged I'm like jumping through my
my skin here Brett over here but right I'm up like I'm up my rocker like Gary
am I a little like excited today the way out the wall my god I can't I'm
ready folks let me get in my mind our guest tonight is John Kiriaka former CIA
officer intelligence analyst covert counterintelligence officer he is
infamously however respectfully but infamously known for breaking the
silence on waterboarding and what was otherwise known as enhanced terror
technique enhanced interrogation techniques which we all do know now was
torture which we all know provided zero and good actionable intelligence John
has lived our tough life with decisions that have marked and changed his life
and on Sonati show folks you know we pull back that curtain we call a spade
a spade and we're gonna tell you who John really is without the spin let's
get through it he's lived through many things and we're gonna get him on in
a second he exposed something just was so despicable that our country would be
engaged in and he's he'll get into it a little bit more but you all know who he
is he's got several books out he's he's everywhere on online I respect that
because I know the heavy weight of what silence can be and John and I will
talk about that because we know each other and we're gonna have a nice
combo I suffer in silence he suffer in silence in a world where truth
isn't convenient it's dangerous truth is dangerous and tonight we're gonna talk
about the danger let's bring in John welcome John to unplug thanks Eric good
to be with you thanks for having John it is absolute pleasure let's just tap for
a second how was life for you right now you know that things have finally
turned around it it took it took the better part of a decade and a half but
so I got things to look up for you know it's kind of a cliche that things
really do get better but they actually do get better so you got to just stick
with it keep your nose down and and work as hard as you can good thing you know
the silence is tough you know what I mean because you have to be beat up
publicly and you can't actually say the truth yeah and in that period where
you need support the most that's when people are the most likely to abandon
you you really get to see who your friends are who your real friends are
and and even family members will decide that your numbers abandon me yeah yeah I
did too you know I'm John we're gonna start up on one little note I'm not gonna
name a country or an AOR you're a legend we served in the same location and I
read some of your stuff you are amazing had a good time I had a good time there
a great location yeah great place people think it's a great location but we
had a good time but yeah you're a legend of your own world I mean truly
thank you for that you know I watched some you watch you on some other shows we
are a radio show so we're live on I heart what we will be downloadable in
every podcast about 30 minutes after the show airs live but I watched some people
do some sandbagging to you so I want to start with one thing John you know
that I'm a trained lawyer and I'm a constitutional I got my book coming
out on Constitution let's get the facts straight folks John was charged
federally not for exposing national secrets that put the country in
jeopardy he never did that he never taught what it never was a convicted or
actually anything with that he was charged with a very weird it's like that
UCMJ the uniform code of military justice at y'all right basically for
identifying an undercover intelligence officer's name which you
accidentally said and I know we don't want to say it but tell me how that
worked out for you that you were not a trader to your nation like oh no
the traders were the ones that put us in a position to do more harm to the
country business and violating Constitution gave up no secrets no no no in
fact at first the Justice Department charged me with three counts of espionage
for blowing the whistle in the torture program and then they declassified the
program in their words for the purpose of prosecution right and they
overreach and then they waited until I went bankrupt and then when I went
bankrupt they dropped all the do and you know there is legislation for using the
justice system which we know gets weaponized all you know selective
prosecution right there they're supposed to be statues for that and any
selectively prosecuted you because we could name and we're not going to
several people that did far worse oh listen I'll name several people who good
name it on my show do it do it do expose the names wait a minute the
people who expose the names of covert operatives like David Petraeus expose
the names of 10 covert operatives to his adulterous girlfriend and there was a
disgruntled for a little tough right yeah and there was a disgraced former CIA
officer from Bethesda Maryland who outed seven CIA officers undercover from the
Bush administration Scooter Libby Libby never exposed anybody's name didn't
he get nails or something what what did he go down for he went down for
perjury it was it was the deputy secretary of state who exposed Valerie
yeah I mean I think that was impivial for me to get out there because nobody
seems to want to tell that upside because you know that actually kind of
vindicate you tremendous yeah now you've gotten your life together are you
understanding you're going on a very large speaking engagement yeah I'm
gonna go on a on a year-long around the world speaking tour starting in two
weeks in Ireland and Northern Ireland if you're in Ireland we're gonna be in
Belfast Cork and Dublin and then a quick side trip to Manchester it's been on
Ireland since you're talking about it what do you think about Belfast in
Dublin you know as that split of iron one doesn't you think that's ever gonna
rectify yeah I do yeah I hope among the British people they don't want Northern
Ireland right it's too much trouble to deal with now since the Good Friday
peace Accords it's been better but what threw a wrench into the situation was
the UK's decision to withdraw from the European Union right now because Ireland's
in the European Union and Britain's not in the European Union you know they
haven't quite figured out exactly the best workable way to handle the border it's
gonna be a big problem and yeah I know you're into the Greek and I believe we
both put a hopped into Cyprus right I actually Brett you know I was talking
to a guy from Cyprus yesterday actually that you know well I'll hit you off
line with him he's a natal guy and he was like what is that language he
was looking at I'm like oh it's Greek but I use using a translator I can't be
Greek you wonder how you understand was the only person in CIA that can speak
Greek and Arabic yeah as crazy as it sounds I was the only person in the
entire CIA that had both Greek and Arabic that's why they sent me to Athens
the seminar Athens primarily to do Arab terrorism secondarily to do Greek
terrorism but it was the Greek terrorists that kept us busy all the
time tell us how did your federal prison experience turn out you know
where I'm going with this it's pretty funny you know we incarcerate far far too
many I wrote an article about that yeah it's terrible you know you know the
statistics and we have 5% of the world's population in the world yeah we
absolutely we have 5% of the world's population we have 25% of the world's
prison population and Congress creates 50 new crimes 50 new felonies every
single year that's something that was legal a year ago that is a felony
today and it's it's just over the top yeah so I wouldn't wish it on anybody but
I I had as easy a time as a person could have worked out for you when you got there
I got I got adopted by the Italians when I arrived and really you know I mean
Italians named Gambino and Lucchese and Bonanno and you know not on day if
it can't they yeah and so they took they took good care of me I you had
good sausage I understand I gained 35 pounds in prison so because of those good
fellow like they I know they brought you wine you got the good life wine and pork
loin and fresh vegetables and pasta yeah but you originally they were trying
to link you up with the Aryan nation people yeah the Aryans were the first
ones to approach me and you know Muslims also supported you yeah it was less
support as as it then it was first I think they were afraid you no no my first
my first day in prison one of the nation of Islam guys came up to me and and
very gingerly handed me a newspaper it was the call it was called it was the
nation of Islam newspaper and he said that that Reverend Farrakhan had said
that I was a hero of the Muslim people and that I wouldn't have any problem
with them and so that was it I never spoke again yeah so the Aryans were the
ones that first approached me and they demand paperwork and when you first
arrive you have to show an official BOP form saying what your crime was and
mine was this obscure violation or yeah I never heard such a section act of
1981 and so because I wasn't gay I wasn't a rat and I wasn't a child
molester then I was okay with the Aryans so how did the five families
approaching I lived across the hall from a captain in the banana like can I ask
obviously both know who it is can you say it or no you know I'd kind of like
to leave him out of it because not only was he good to me but we remain
friends and we remain in touch and yeah I think I should leave him out but he
asked me one day I had a subscription the New York Times and he had a
subscription the New York Post and so at the end of the day we would trade
papers and then we would sit and watch you know football together sometimes
baseball and so he asked me one day he says let me ask you a question why do
you sit with those Nazi retards in the and I said I don't know when I my first
day here they they looked at my paperwork they told me to sit with them
and he said from today you're with the Italians but you're Greek you're
close to the Romans yeah yeah yeah very much so and you know in all
you had a you had a bodyguard service that walked every way you walked in the
facility it wasn't for me so much as it was for the actual boss of the Gambino
would it be the person that I sent you a picture of him and I know no no it was
somebody above the other guy all right yeah I got you was he wasn't there
when you were there the picture no we just missed each other yeah I thought so
everybody everybody knows where everybody else is like there was a
guy there's another guy you know a guy right they do they all know a guy and
they all have these networks on the outside and so two weeks in advance we
knew so-and-so was coming or this other guy was coming in and he's a stand-up guy
or he's a rat or whatever and so you know how to treat people it's a friend of
art yeah exactly you know honestly the mafia did a little lucky Luciano worked
for the agency during World War two yeah he did I mean to protect the
Brooklyn ports yeah yeah I mean they you know that's how I mean that's what
created the Longshoremen Union and that's why they get left alone forever that's
right so tell me what it what has been the most difficult thing that you've had
to overcome because of all this nonsense the right thing yeah that that's
actually an easy question you know most most people in prison think that when
their sentence is up they can just step back into their lives again and you
can't you don't realize how depressed you are you don't realize how much anxiety
you have and you certainly don't realize that you're suffering from PTSD yeah and
you get out and you think you could just just start right back up again and
you can't that's number one number two many people also under estimate the
impact that the whole experience had on their families that's hard to maybe
the hardest though is you just will not be able to get a job period you and I were
talking offline I got rejected at every grocery store I got rejected at Target
and McDonald's and I got rejected as a baggage handler at the airport I couldn't
buy a job and so you know I had a couple of little bones thrown my way I
got a job at a at a think tank in Washington they wanted me to write about
you know prison reform issues but minimum ways and I'm a good writer I've
published you know eight books so far I made the New York Times best
sellers list I won one of the country's four biggest literary awards so I'm a
good writer but I was making 24 grand I think you're reluctant fine was your
best one thank you that's the one that in doing time like a spider the two
I like that too but I didn't like the prison aspect because I just felt like
yeah it was tough yeah exactly and you know it's funny that's the only one of my
books that I've not reread I believe it because you probably hurt during that one
yeah it my heart starts to race you know the next question is going to make
your heart race but it's no it's not a same big question so exposing
something as powerful as CIA's interrogations program isn't an easy
decision and I truly honor and respect the fact that you did that because you
saved the lives thank you a lot of people did not want to be there for that
I appreciate I remember that I know when that went down they weren't sure where
stuff was coming from and everybody got yanked into skips or folks out there
that don't want to skip this would you like to tell them what a skip is yeah it's
a secure communications center it's a secure it's a revolted area can be as
small as a little conference room it can be as big as the entire floor of a
building but it's got it's got windows that can't be penetrated by laser
beams it's it soundproofed you can you can leave classified documents out in a
skiff and and not when this came out they didn't know where everything was coming
from John so they they were pulling everybody in into skips and they were
making people sit there and they were there was the forensics guys are
going through computers like crazy well I'll tell you what that actually wasn't
me I blew the whistle all at once in a nationally televised interview on ABC
news in December what's the name Brian Ross yes but there had been leaks
starting in 2005 and I was in that location and 05 actually it was the
international came out with a report saying that CIA was torturing its
prisoners human rights watch came out with a report you know six saying CIS
torturing its prisoners American and International Red Cross did a report
07 CIS torturing its prisoners I confirmed it I was not the originator
of the information right out there so you didn't expose anything and that's why
the Bush administration didn't charge me with a crime they said that the
information you know what he was doing they shouldn't be doing either yeah it's
a crime to classify a crime I mean that's an international war crime so
when you made that call to speak out did you feel like the system that you
served for so long and let's get real you started off in a desk job and
you were pre-911 myself 911 too that's what got me into the game and you
went operational as myself I went operational in in 97 so I had I had a
couple of operational tours all in counterterrorism operations before that
and then I had I had also finished the advanced counterterrorism operations
course so I was ready to go yes but you took that one or you're not allowed
to I can't say they split up to different facilities it was all domestic
out west right with the driving and stuff yeah yeah yeah driving was not
drove the big Ranger trucks in the expeditions right exactly good times right
yeah I loved it yeah I do listen are we the best drivers though oh my god still
still to this day and you can't you can't trade you can't follow me it's funny
they they drove that training into you so hard it's not like I took that class
I took the first running of it in 1993 I took the second running in the spring
of 2000 so we're talking about 25 years ago I took that course and still in my
mind I remember it like I took it last week yeah it's just muscle memory it is
it's like I mean I guess all the counter surveillance stuff I mean my head is on
a swivel 24-7 no matter what yeah yeah everything you know operation I'm
prepared 24-7 so I wanted that so did you feel like I mean obviously I know you
felt like did you think that they were gonna not fully turn against you the
way they did because so many people do applaud you but they were afraid to speak
out you know and that's that's the reason why I waited for clearances if
anybody said anything got the bit I waited for four years before I said it I said
something four and a half years because I kept waiting for somebody else to come
out and do it there were so many people reporting back from the secret site that
they were objecting like vehemently objecting to this torture program I
say the location of the specifics of a specific site you can I can't right
I won't then because I know because I was right close to there so it's never been
declassified so I just said okay good thank you so I just expected somebody to
come forward and do something about it and nobody did and then they were gonna
charge you honestly it dragged on forever yeah it dragged on forever I mean the
Bush administration elected to not charge me they sent my attorney a
declination letter saying that they had concluded that I hadn't broken the
law and then you know I know Obama was talking about parting you know he wasn't
there was conversation about people that was scuttlebutt on that no I know
you're a fan of his book you read it or something I hated his book but you had
it on the interview with that yeah yeah yeah it was so self-serving was that
enough you is that what I get it now I just somebody dropped it up a little
very very fun the Greek American community rallied to my side and there
were several very important Greek Americans that asked him to pardon me and
his exact words were guys I'm just not gonna do this it's either him or it's
Manning and Manning got 35 years and so I didn't get it yeah now we're both gonna
be in the same location next week do you think that gentleman will we're
gonna be at the same event is you think he'll help you I don't know man I've
got a fan of three letter agencies no he's not and he's been a supporter of
mine you know he is and he spoke out publicly about you he did any any he
tweeted at me when he was when he was president and I'm hoping that something
good can come of it unbelievable you know operational insight programs like these
just don't appear they're built and approved over time and my question is
who's the architect in this program that we even know that obviously it's
classified at that I don't know your level I mean I know your level of what
we got I thought this is the USAP isn't it that's you know there's an old saying
that success has thousand fathers but defeat has or failure has but one right
in the agency they still consider this to be a successful program and so there
are a dozen different people I can't name one time I saw any piece of
actionable Intel that was actually verifiable yeah there was that
produced anything there was none I mean I mean we've all been waterboarded and it's
terrible I mean you will tell your torturer anything anything they make that
stop wants to hear just to make him stop why don't you explain to people what
it really feels like oh it very much feels like you're drowning cases like in
the case of Abu Zubaydah he did drown and his heart stopped so that he
could be tortured more you know that program actually created some of the
combat medic programs because the doctors would no longer do it because of
the Hippocratic Oath that's right well actually that kind of advanced army
medicine because combat medics are now PAs because they somebody needed to do this
they objected in writing most of them too I mean there were doctors from the
CIA's Office of Medical Services writing cables and saying whoa wait a minute I
didn't sign up for this I took an oath to first do no harm I'm not going
to drown this guy and many of them curtailed their their assignments
which is a career-ending decision right once you do that your game's over some
of them you know resign now you have no pension anything now no they see my
pension is that disgrace yeah all the good things you've done and honestly
again folks out there we're going commercial free on this show again
folks John will be on the hostile zone Monday night 7 p.m. on I heart radio
you'll be back again for some different conversation with a different
crowd got to put that plug in but again folks he was never ever convicted nor
really charged of disclosing government secrets or anything like that you
didn't Edward Snowden no Chelsea Manning what is it
Bradley Manning Chelsea Manning what is it who knows and they got they let him
into Harvard they gave yeah yeah they gave him an admission to Harvard yeah I
know I did I just ruin your day even more you're going on your speaking
engagement next week you're gonna be a millionaire don't worry about I will
say I met Chelsea Manning once her request but Chelsea Manning is not a part
of the whistleblower community either in government or in Washington or
nationally not a player not a participant nobody that I know is in
contact with her oh Snowden's a giant yeah Snowden's a giant I have the
deepest possible respect for him you know I wouldn't have done it the way he
did it can I bring up an interview you did with somebody
Andrew and what was the month yeah boost the month Andrew he looked a lot
different years ago what was that show you who's who's who's show we are was the
Danny Jones pocket yeah I like Danny I think he's an asset he is
screaming an asset Rex Freeman is he an asset I don't have any idea I think he
might be an NLC I don't know well if he is if he is you try to get it a
felony he's really good I'm just talking Joe care of life he's so good
he's just really the best he really is good have you been on his show let's know
he is so calculated with his questions he is really good that's how many Joneses
Danny Jones is great too the gifted interviewer and when my edit my my
executive producer she's going to get the clip so Dan Andrew boost a month
date is a former CIA officer himself yes he has a thing called every day
spiable that's right and and he basically sells tradecraft yes two
businesses to promote business whatever I have no comment on what he does with his
life I really have nothing negative Andrew I got nothing negative to say
about you but what happened to you on that particular episode it was a nice
conversation and then he called you a traitor and he said you and Snowden
tell us what happened Danny Jones had asked us months in advance if we would
agree to a debate and I readily said yes it was so then it was spirited and
the truth is we agreed on probably every cent yeah of what we were talking
again he just slipped on you yeah we're gonna she's gonna run it the clip but
tell us what happened I mean I mean how did you feel at that moment I mean talk
about being sampled oh no listen to me he's just some kid who happened to
spend a couple of years in the agency I was not intimidated by him at all and
you know a few days before that debate I remember thinking should I prepare for
this in some way and then I thought no if I don't know these these issues by now
I'm never gonna know him I'm like one of the country's leading experts on these
issues right you say everywhere I speak everywhere all the time and I've written
you know seven of my of my books are about the CIA so no I don't need to
prepare and my attorney my attorney later texted me he's not just a
constitutional lawyer Harvard and Harvard law he was also the deputy attorney
general of the United States and he texted me and he said you gave that kid a
masterclass in the Constitution you school so yeah I did I I was very proud of
my view like that he got he got frustrated and so he called me a trader
because I had a show on a Russian radio network I was ancient here in the
United States yeah it was terrestrial radio here in the radio correct
but yeah we thought it was Washington DC and was sanctioned on the airways
here in America yeah it's like BBC what do you call your trade if you're on BBC
exactly there we go folks there it is so John let's get this let's get to something
better I just wanted to set the record straight for you on that thank you so your
experience came from much of real-world operation versus political pressure from
the people who have been in the field now we know how it works in this game
you get a pencil neck political appointee that comes in and thinks that
they're gonna change a career operative analyst agent officer whatever
and you know that they're gonna do that how did that affect you because you know
that those are the people that came at you hard there wasn't agency insiders
coming for you it was political hacks it was political hacks who had been agency
insiders yeah I mean are the lifetime agency people that have been in there
and they're never going anywhere that's what I'm talking so you got your
political appointees and then these people that are there are no there are
no political appointees at the CIA other than the director director but I
mean like the high-level SCS special executive service whatever yeah we have
the we have this for the senior senior intelligence service
SIS and then they're there for 25 30 35 years yeah and they don't leave now
John Brennan had left he had retired and had gone on John Brennan now yeah I
mean he had gone to some comments I made about him on a show on yeah
silent here's the mutual respect I want to take a second to acknowledge the
risks that you took that kind of decision just I can't imagine because
obviously well you know what happened to me and you know that I can't say
anything maybe you can help me with that what do you think I mean what what
say you on that I made with that I was completely directionless when I got
home from prison I was in prison for 23 months had this minimum wage job went
to work for a very very small medical devices company completely on commission
was not able to contribute to the well-being of my family and so I just
decided to well actually it was my ex-wife we were still married at the
time and she said okay family she said you have to embrace this you can't like
hide from it you have to embrace it and you've got a so boxing and very
tough so she was right I started writing writing writing like that's what I
mean I got to the point where a publishing house called me and they
commissioned a book that turned out to be my third book and I said that was the
convenient tear I like that one thank you that's out of all my books that one is
the most highly rated very operational very hanging on the seat of your
chair I tried hard to make it like that to make it read like I'm gonna be
sure to put plugs you have at the end give us links the way they can get
these books oh thanks they're all on Amazon so publishing house called me
and said can you write this book I said yeah sure I need the money anyway and
they said it's from the agency to write your books I if I write a letter to
home and garden magazine I need a clearance from the agent how long does
it take you to get a return for approval well it they asked me if I
would write this book I said yes and they said well we needed in we needed
in 30 days and I said 30 days I said it takes me nine months to write a
book and they said yeah we needed 30 days so I told my wife I am gonna sit at
this computer every day and I'm not gonna get up until I've written at least a
thousand words I started writing the day after Thanksgiving and I finished the
day before Christmas and got it out in 30 days and then I thought you know what
I'm actually pretty good at this book thing then they came back and they
commissioned form for anyone else right thank one else no it was the my first
was Random House my second was an imprint of Simon and Schuster this was
Sky Horse oh they did my third through my seventh and then I shopped my eighth
book around and they took it they took the eighth book as well so I mean I
have I have my best relationship with with Sky Horse there they're wonderful
wonderful and they did Bobby Kennedy's book and they did Melania
Trump's book and they have they have some big name authors but I they've done
right by me so I just decided you know what the more I write the more I'm gonna
get out there and the more I get out there the more I'm gonna rehabilitate
myself and it culminated the week before COVID started I got a call from the
commandant of West Point inviting me to speak the first year class on ethics
in intelligence operations you're now you're now a champion in the game yeah it
worked out and then that led to countless podcasts and the podcast
it's suffering in silence that's what I'm asking like when you're when you're like
you know well you know what's going on with me yeah so what I've experienced
it's tough you can't say anything and you got to sit there and you got to be
the dirtbag that people want to say that's where you're wrong that's
where you're wrong you can say something you can say the government's full of shit
the cops are full of shit I didn't do what they're accusing me of doing and if they
want to have this argument let's have it in public are you sure do you think any
of that was real with me of course not thank you heard it right from a real
professional here there you go I mean it's terrible they did it and you know
you see who wrote some of that stuff and you see their narrative of who they
are well there was a hatchet job by NPR and NPR tried to hatch a job on
me too and you know it's funny they tried and I wouldn't I wouldn't stand for it
so they called me and they said hey we'd like to have you on whatever that that
show is on Saturday mornings I forget whatever it is and so I said yeah sure
because I always I always say yes so I go all the way up to NPR up on Capitol
Hill and they're so nice to me here's a bottle of water here's a cup of
coffee they bring me into the studio we sat down as soon as they hit the report
button they attack and I said oh no you wouldn't hear the next call when they
called me I said I don't know who you I said oh no you don't I'm not gonna
take it from you or from anybody else I said listen I don't answer to NPR I
said if you're gonna if you're gonna invite me to come on and have a
conversation I'll come on and have a conversation it would I could be on
just me I'm not gonna play games like that with you and I got up and I
walked out they actually clipped it down to like two minutes I did the dog an
interview on Saturday morning I just ignored it I got a call from a professor
friend of mine who said wow I just heard this clip on NPR you really gave it to
him and I was like huh I can't believe they had the balls to actually run it
but they never called me again and that's perfectly fine with me now what
happened not MP then but another news outlet which I don't want to spark a
war with them again I could not get anybody to interview interview me at all
which was terrible I mean and you know the facts it is stuff you know it's
complete nonsense and you know who I am and you know me so I don't need to go
any further with that I did do an interview on my phone and they I sent
it to them and they took 10 seconds yeah they had to interview they're quite
good at that because it ran in narrative but that sheriff is out of
office yeah bye bye bye bye John that's good well I'll tell you a funny story I
got a call on time this is in like 20 I'm gonna say 17 or 18 I got a call from the
Washington Post and I've written for the post a couple of times it's not
unusual for them to call me but the guy calls the reporter and he said hey
I was wondering if I could get a quote from you on Peter Strock you remember
Peter Strock was the FBI agent yeah had you know take over his his adulterous
girlfriend about Trump yeah the crazy man it never happened but it was right
there right right so I said I said well I'm happy to talk to you guys but I
don't know any any more about Peter Strock than what I've read in the
Washington Post and he says no Peter Strock is the FBI agent who arrested
you and I said that was Peter Strock he was new he said yeah I went through the
I went through the paperwork and it was Peter Strock who put the cuffs on you I
said oh yeah I'll give you a comment give you a comment now and I said I said in
Washington people have long memories and karma is a bitch thank you and that's
what they that's what they printed and you know what and the downfall
lies it happens and they escorted him out of FBI headquarters they took his
gun in his badge and took him by the arms and escorted him out of FBI headquarters
just as he deserved absolutely but did he get charged really no you know what
the son of the gun the son of the gun raised over a hundred twenty thousand
dollars on GoFundMe to pay his legal bills too which really made me mad
and it donated to the Biden administration too I thought I think he
probably did because he never ended up going to trial he was looking for a
pardon yeah you so did you watch any of the hearings on the on the hill yeah
did you see Pete handed himself well he did you know out of out of all the
about Pete he's the incoming Secretary of Defense Jeff formerly of Fox News listen
for me personally I think he's a terrible choice because he's not qualified I
think that's where Trump wants that he wants a man a man of assault you don't
put somebody with no qualifications in charge of a one trillion dollar company
with three million employees like what are you thinking he handed himself like
a pro today though yeah you know like but the questions were you know when did
you stop beating your wife when you fathered that child you think that was
really appropriate though yeah does that have anything to do with this position
it but it has to do with character okay I get you I guess clearance purposes
right but hey Barack Obama didn't qualify for security clearance sure he
did really it was reported with issues oh he was a member of the
intelligence committee I don't know I'm just telling you reports that came
across and I'm not taking anything classified here I just read again I wasn't
involved with that point I don't want him coming after me but strike that what do
you think it's Tulsi Gamber like her a lot like her a lot you think she's gonna
make institutional change in the IC no and I'll tell you why tell me why there
are 18 intelligence agencies that make up the American you watch my episode on
that I did a whole episode identifying each one well there are only two
members of the intelligence community that do not fall under the jurisdiction of the
Secretary of Defense CIA and the State Department's Bureau of Intelligence and
Research right and so the only thing that Tulsi Gabbard's going to be in charge of
is the intelligence community budget which is important but not important and
it's a huge influence on the DIA no any NRO no no those are both DOD agencies
so she is very connected with DOD no right we're gonna have a secretary she's
still is she still in the guard yeah she is she's interesting no yeah Lindsey
Graham is still a an Air Force member the Judge Advocate General I did not know
that wow I need to get him on the show that'd be interesting interview so
she's she has primacy over the intelligence community budget and she
also heads the the PDB the president's daily brief that's it the matrix it's
John Ratcliffe that is gonna be that is gonna be right yeah the main player
right what do you think of a Mike Flynn he needs a pardon I personally would
pardon Mike Flynn I don't think Mike Flynn should have ever been charged with
a crack he was another one set up yeah I think he was set up now I think he
should have been charged with not registering under under Farah he was
clearly obviously you are taking money from a foreign government for the
purpose of promoting the the positions or policies of that government you have to
fill out a form called the foreign agents registration act form Farah it's it
takes 10 minutes you go to Farah dot gov and you just fill it out I mean he
wasn't doing anything illegal he just needed to file it he did not file it
right he was he was representing the another stupid little government then he
was representing the government of Turkey right and and never registered and
then there was famously reported in the Wall Street Journal about a week before
Donald Trump became president there was a meeting in a New York hotel where
Flynn was meeting with members of the Turkish National Intelligence
Organization the TINIA and and former CIA director Jim Woolsey went to the
meeting he was five minutes late and when he walked in Flynn was offering the
Turks he was offering to kidnap Fatullah Gulen a Turkish oppositionist who lived
outside of Pittsburgh and turn him over to the Turks and Woolsey said oh my god
you're committing a felony it's not the guy that has the perimeter around
this property yeah and so Woolsey walked out of the meeting and then
immediately called the FBI this is over that uprising that occurred in Turkey
where they get the tense and everything I remember yeah yeah so Flynn should
have been charged with that felony he wasn't he was charged for a felony that
he actually didn't commit and got a pardon he's a good guy I want to I
think he's a religious nut to tell you the trigger we're gonna agree to
disagree I like Mike what's your take on Pompeo oh Pompeo is a scum I was
waiting for you know I have a friend who was one of Pompeo's bodyguards in the
CIA's Office of Security and we had we had lunch one day and I said so how are
things going over there and he said let me tell you the only person who is
less popular than Mike Pompeo is Mrs. Mike Pompeo he said all she does is
snap her fingers and say dog you go pick up my dry cleaning you shovel the
snow and they're like yeah we're here to protect your husband so I have you I
want you to tell a funny story and Kelly's gonna have to bleep it out because
we're radio oh that's a guy that made a comment to you about a genitalia tell
that story I love it but Jenna tell you remember he said I have a better
than bigger than you oh that was when I got a great story when I got hired
agency I know it's okay for radio okay I know the truth the truth of the story is
okay for radio I was in grad school at George Washington that works because
people don't understand how NOC positions work so I was not a knockoff
no I mean this guy was no no it wasn't a press saying I don't I'm not really a
professor yeah yeah he was yeah I mean that to the people where do you want
me to start stories both stories I'm trying to get it all in in time frame
so I was in grad school at George Washington University I was taking this
class it called the psychology of leadership it was taught by Dr. Gerald
Post was a psychiatrist and eminent psychiatrist he had a PhD in political
science a PhD in psychology and an MD all from Yale and
pardon me it's going don't gang oh I have no idea I doubt it he was
Jewish so not not gonna happen okay yeah so he signed us this paper where we
had to shadow our bosses for a week and then write a psychological evaluation of
our bosses and I was working for a union at the time the United Food and
Commercial Workers Union and I was working for this guy was a real real
tough guy like old school union organizer he had his back broken
during a strike scabs beat him up and broke his back real tough guy and I
was a little bit afraid of it so I'm shadowing him this one week and we got
into an argument and I called him a racist and he squared he squared up and
put his fists up in the air and I put up my hands to protect myself and I
thought oh no I went too far this time but instead of hitting me he says my
penis is bigger than yours I said what and he said it again my penis is
bigger than yours and I said you know what your nuts and I quit and I
walked out I quit so I went back to my apartment I wrote this paper and I
wrote it very comprehensively and passed the paper in a week later I get the
paper back and I got an A and Dr. Post wrote in the margin please see me
after class so I went up to him after class and and said Dr. Post you
wanted to see me and he said yeah close the door so I closed the door
and he said look I'm not really a professor here I'm undercover I'm a
CIA officer undercover as a professor here were you saying that professors could
possibly be actually working in the intelligence community in place as a
professor until 1993 yes right yeah yeah in 1993 I mean before 1993 this is
the way that people got recruited right this is the way that most that most
operations officers were recruited that's why everybody was white everybody
was male everybody went to a great school on the east coast you know
that's just the way it was and then in 1993 Congress passed the equal
employment the equal opportunity the equal employment opportunity act
who I will talk about that a minute and yeah I mean it inadvertently weakened
the agency to tell you the truth but yeah he made some calls I mean I had to
do it all on my own I had to take the tests pass the tests polygraphs
background investigation you have to give them some of your blood some of
your piss some of your hair psychological testing your right hair or did they
take it from your head they plucked it because they need the they need the
root they plucked it from your head and and then I made it I made it and but
they don't do that anymore now they do it overtly it's something similar but
it's over where they created this this program we're facing job is what I was
trying to articulate sitting say that again people have positions that are
forward-facing position but they're really doing something else exactly
you know where I'm going with this yeah so what they do now they have this
program called the scholar in residence program so if you're two or three
years before retirement they'll ask you if you want to go back to your alma mater
as a CIA officer who's going to teach a couple of classes and then while you're
there you essentially do the same kind of spotting you just don't do it
secretly you do it overtly now since you kind of touch on that can you
explain a little bit what a a unrecognized that like an NOC sort of
is yeah a knock officer knock stands for national I'm sorry it stands for non
official cover so Emerilist Fox Kennedy who was Bobby Kennedy's is Bobby
Kennedy's daughter-in-law and was his campaign manager she's now rumored to
be the next deputy national security advisor hear that yeah she was a knock
officer so where I was under official cover working in American embassies
around the world and most CIA officers are under official cover it's only like
10% or NOC's yeah less than that it's more like six so she was she was an art
dealer that was her cover or you know maybe you can be a wildlife photographer
or the head of a mutual now as you're not gonna be the content of people who
have the information if you were in Mike the New York area post 9-11 yeah we
wouldn't have a knock officer domestically and at the M1 and I well I mean
unless the firefighters a Muslim and it's going to go into a mosque but
otherwise you who gives a key conversation there yeah what did you
think about that when they were going to build the mosque right there on ground
zero yeah I was I was listen I consider myself a lifelong leftist and I was
adamantly opposed to that mosque and I'll tell you why I'm and my position
comes from a selfish place and I don't care and I don't make any any excuse
right but the reason I felt so strongly about it is there was one church at
ground zero it was St. Nicholas Greek Orthodox Church it was built in 1927 and
it was there from the beginning right 50 years 45 years later was when the
towers went up and so our church was right there at the towers it was
vaporized on 9-11 and so if any religious building any house of worship was
going to serve it right it was going to be the Greek Orthodox Church of St. Nicholas
and that's what is now at ground zero right have you been bound to ground
zero since I've never been there many times have you been here I've never gone
into the museum or even been into the tower I'm not exaggerating when I
tell you it took me 20 years before I could go into the museum has never
gone I can't I've never done it it was too painful yeah it was too much I finally
went through it a year ago and you were at the Pentagon at the time you were at
the you were in in headquarters I was at CIA headquarters yeah I understand you
when your wife watched the burning from the house and you like I got to go
back to work yeah yeah we went to the roof of the apartment building watch
the panic burn from the Marriott yeah we did we stole 10 $15,000 worth of
food from the mayor the Marriott ran the cafeteria at the CIA and when
everybody evacuated and they chained it closed and so a bunch of us at the
counterterrorism center we broke the lock in the chain and and we just cooked
all the food and just laid it out for everybody to graze on because we were
there for days like without without leaving I slept under my desk you
know an hour or two at a time everybody did and so I got a good question for
you that you never get asked and we talked about it before you were
involved with the movie Zero Dark Thirty no not Zero Dark Thirty I you know Dan
Ellsberg called me when Zero Dark Thirty came out and he said you've got to do a
review of this movie for the Washington Post because you're the only person who
could do it from a position of having been on the inside and so I went to the
movie I was gonna skip it I went to see it and I hated it because it
perpetuated the lie that torture led to the location about of that we
ended up screwing over yeah it was who's still in prison in Pakistan but I did
consult on on the kite runner I consulted on on Bruno I consulted on kill the
messenger which is about you know the CIA and cocaine and I think also with was
it that something of spies with DiCaprio no I did true lies Schwarzenegger
I knew I could remember I was I also did from Paris with love with with John
Travolta and they really they were kind to me they even put a special thanks at
the end of the movie right that's all I mean Hollywood is deeply in bed with
the agencies deep I mean I tell people all the time look at the movie Argo
yeah yeah although that stuck as close to the truth is you got the good
legit that was a legit movie you know the CIA's Office of Public Affairs has a
branch that's dedicated solely to liaising with Hollywood and that's something
that the FBI did you know for 60 years before this they get all the access the
inside of stuff to get equipment and we get to promote our image yeah that's
right so well we're coming up to a hard hold but you're gonna be back on the
show let me see what I had a whole bunch of things I want to say is there
anything you want to ask me John I mean we haven't shattered let's have it what
let's do the last four minutes let's have a condom here over here Brett is
dying yes you want to ask sure sure he's like a huge fan of yours for sure thank
you and he's gonna be a host of a new public safety show on I heart very good
appears so good here's your chance buddy yeah Eric's Eric's kind of selling
me out which is one of one of those good things you know especially when it
comes from a good brand and a good name yep um first of all John war hero you
know a lot of us here thank you love some of the work John was a guy Brett he was
a contractor with the military thank it was one of those things you know great
opportunity loved it loved what we did but I just want to know personally how
are you doing now thank God I this is gonna be a life-changing year for me
personally it's taken me ten years to get back on my feet ten tell me that very
moving to think it's it's hard I won't sugarcoat it my marriage broke up and and
so I've gone it alone so it was hard but it really does turn around you just
have to work until you can't work anymore I barely sleep all I do is
right and and in the end it paid off so this is gonna be you know knock on
wood if I could find some wood knock on wood for you yeah it's called Tigers Lane
Studios it's based in London they also represented the the two DEA agents who
killed Pablo Escobar so I'm their second speaking client and they've booked a
100 event one year around the world speaking tour we're already sold out
in Belfast we're almost sold out in Belfast is the 29th Dublin is the 30th
and and Manchester England is the first we're adding cork and then I'm gonna go
I'm gonna come back here for a few weeks then go back to the UK for 42
dates in the UK so if you go to Tigers Lane Studios comm the schedule is there
and add up for you and thank you thank you I'm Brett how'd you feel your first
moment on the air see I told you should do it he was stressing it all day please
don't make me oh yeah I'm not gonna lie I was a little bit nervous put a plug for
your show public safety unplugged safety zone unplugged yes going with the
bridge going with the bridge I love that he reminds me of the zone it's
one of those things well you are on my network yes yes yes and we have some
your friends John coming on too so we're gonna be looking forward to John was
kind enough to introduce us to several talent great John what would you like
to chat with me for two minutes about well you know rather than ask you
questions I want to reiterate what I said earlier you know it's been my
experience man that this is not the way my life was supposed to play out right
yeah yeah I was always the good kid I got great grades I went to good
school got a bachelor's degree got a master's degree did my PhD course work
great schools and went to the CIA did really cool stuff 12 exceptional
performance awards the sustained superior performance award I met with
presidents and kings and prime ministers I went to 72 countries for my my
government I wasn't supposed to end up in prison and on the unemployment line
but these things happen for a purpose I've really come to believe that they
happen for a purpose and now that it's all said and done I realize and it wasn't
it wasn't a period of self-realization it was John McCain who told me that this
is why I was put on the earth that the American people would never have had
any idea what the government was doing in their name if I hadn't told them
so even though it seems like life may have taken a dump right on your head
there's a silver lining here and that's overlining may be as simple and as
obvious as putting a fire under your feet to get on the air and talk about
these issues that other people are ignoring so keep the faith as a fake
news is killing me you know yeah exactly exactly and so we have to
confront that head-on and that's why that's why the hostile zone was created
and removed and followed but you know like I find to my box and trolls the same
news story that has fake news always pops up number three so I hired it I hired
it a major former government contractor to really spook it and there's box
there's somebody's paying box see keep it up there but you can never trace
them they're out of China I'm sure that that's true and I'll take another
thing there was I had a real story I mean you know how atrocious it is
oh yeah I had a detractor on on Twitter who would just like hit me every day just
she's constantly just hitting me hitting me hitting me and I just ignored her but
she's got a quarter of a million followers and then she went too far one
night and I decided you know what I'm gonna sue I'm gonna be that guy I'm
gonna be that guy who's not directly somebody for that because it
nobody wants help and I sued and she fell apart immediately first of all within 48
hours she agreed to pin a retraction for six months it was a retraction that my
attorney wrote and then she had to apologize in a tweet every day for 30
days I love it and then she paid my she paid my legal fees would you make
a referral for me because we're out Matt he actually made threats if I
brought somebody in from outside but your guy is they're not gonna play with him nope
I would love that I mean you ready for you it's atrocious yeah I mean but you
know so John's gonna be with us again on the hostile zone and you'll get to meet
them and meet to be lovely Bianca SEA what have you heard a lovely voice you
need to pay attention she's amazing how rendition of national anthem is amazing
so John I ultimately thank you with sincere gratitude for what you've done
for our nation I wish you the best in your speaking engagement I seriously was
serious I want to take it up I'm sure I can good good good I'll be in the
front row cheering you on brother fantastic and I see you Monday night John
you have any final saying word two second word thanks for having me thanks
for a good conversation great this will be here Thursday night 7 p.m. Eastern
and it will be on all the stations and it'll be in every podcast 30 minutes
after that we will talk to you all fair stay on for a second
and you see what's up
who's brush your eyes and right
for the rest of the history
that I've been like with Steve
and she's not going anywhere
oh say our spangled banner
for the